# Claudio Villanueva

Address: 630 Amunategui Apt 304, Santiago, Chile

Mobile: +56 9563 777 38 E-mail: claudioff@gmail.com

Nationality: Chilean

#### **Personal Profile**

I am passionate about software development, with around 12 years of experience building software and 8 years with iOS and Android apps. Besides considering myself as a mobile specialist I really enjoy learning new languages and technologies and I have a lot of ductility to work with all kind of software projects.

#### **Achievements**

- Have recently designed and migrated to Clean Architecture an iOS application with more than 500,000 users.
- Have designed a commercial TV detection application from scratch using image hashing algorithms.
- Have designed a mobile messaging system from scratch including iOS, Android, API and database.

#### **Education**

#### 2003 – 2007 Bachelor in Computer Science – Engineering – University of Santiago

· Best bachelor's degree.

#### 2011 – 2012 Japanese Language – Kudan Institute – Tokyo – Japan

· Mid level, Working and daily life proficiency.

#### 2008 – 2010 English classes with a particular teacher

· Fluent in English. Business level proficiency.

# 1995 – 1998 Mid Level Electronics Technician – Technical High School

# **Employment**

## March 2020 to Present – iOS developer at Transbank – Santiago, Chile

- iOS apps development.
- IOS apps design & architecture.
- Team leading, junior developers mentoring and training.
- iOS apps CI/CD.
- Git repository management.

#### March 2019 to March 2020 - iOS Developer at WOM - Santiago, Chile

- iOS apps development.
- IOS apps design & architecture.
- Team leading, junior developers mentoring and training.
- iOS apps CI/CD.
- Git repository management.

#### April 2017 to January 2020 – Mobile developer R&D at Garapon Inc – Tokyo, Japan

- iOS & Android apps development and CI/CD.
- Research and development of computer vision based apps.
- API development.
- Linux apps development.
- Programming and optimization for big volume video data processing.

## April 2013 to March 2017 – Software Developer at Pixtoome – Santiago, Chile

- iOS & Android apps design & development.
- API design & development.
- Database modeling.
- Web development.

# December 2009 to March 2013 - Software Developer at Ubix - Santiago, Chile

- iOS, Android and Java Micro Edition apps design & development.
- API design & development.
- Database modeling.
- Web development.

# July 2001 to November 2009 – Systems Administrator at Grau – Santiago, Chile

- Unix & Linux systems administration.
- Database administration.
- ERP systems Administration.

## Skills

- Excellent knowledge of mobile apps related languages and SDK, including Swift, Java, Objective C, Kotlin, Android NDK and Apple frameworks. Releasing apps in stores. Debugging and profiling.
- Medium level knowledge of lower level languages such as C and C++. Experience programming high performance apps, and apps for embedded Linux devices.
- Good knowledge of Linux servers languages and software like PHP, Python, Java, Scala, Golang, Perl, Bash script, PostgreSQL, MySQL, ZeroMQ, RabbitMQ and Docker.
- Web development using Java frameworks, Javascript and CSS.
- Cloud resources management, AWS, Azure and Google.
- APIs development, microservices and containers deployment. Database modeling.
- Machine Learning models training.
- Continuous integration and delivery with Jenkins, Hudson and Ansible.
- RxSwift, Fastlane and a diversity of tools used for iOS development.

# References

Rene Ramirez

Ubix CEO +569 8837 2892

Javier Ergas

Pixtoome CEO +569 9871 5243

# **Portfolio, Repos and Demos**

https://cvillanueva.github.io check out my professionally made apps.

https://github.com/cvillanueva my demo repositories.

https://cvillanueva.github.io/aquila a shoot'em up Game.

https://cvillanueva.github.io/Labyrintho a 3D Maze adventure.